wizzair.com 2017-06-21

# Privacy Policy

### 1\. BACKGROUND

Wizz Air Hungary Kft. (“Wizz Air” or “we” or “us”) (registered seat: Laurus Offices | Kőér street 2/A | Building B | H-1103 | Budapest, Hungary; registration number: 01-09-964332) pays special attention to data protection. Data processing by Wizz Air complies with the relevant Hungarian data protection laws and is carried out in accordance with this Policy. Wizz Air is a registered data controller at the registry maintained by the Hungarian National Authority for Data Protection and Freedom of Information (the registration number related to the processing of passenger data is 01001, the registration number related to direct marketing is NAIH-83118/2015, and the registration number related to database development is NAIH-83120/2015).

### 2\. THE INFORMATION WE ASK FOR AND USE OF YOUR DATA

2.1 Personal dataThis Policy applies to all personal data you provide us or we collect and process in association with your relationship with Wizz Air. For the purposes of this Policy “personal data” means any information relating to you from which you are or can be identified, directly or indirectly (in particular your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, credit or bank card number, information on special care) and any reference drawn from such information pertaining to you.

2.2 Collection of your personal dataWhenever you use our services or services offered by third parties on our website (e.g. you proceed with a booking for a flight or air transport service or any related activities) we collect personal data about you either provided by you to us (or our agent) directly or collected by us when you used our services or booked third parties’ services on our website. However, Wizz Air is not responsible for third parties’ use of your data, where such use is permitted, for their own purposes. In such cases please consult their privacy policies for further information. You can find more information about the data transfers to third parties in section 3 below.

2.3 Information we collect and process:  
\- information about you,  
\- information about the services you purchased (whether directly provided by us or by our agent),  
\- the details of your travel arrangements (for instance the details of your booking and the additional services we provided),  
\- details of your use of our website (including but not limited to your historical bookings which you did not finish), call centers or mobile applications and  
\- information about communication you have with us and our staff.

 **By providing us with your personal data, you acknowledge and explicitly consent to Wizz Air processing your personal data in accordance with this Policy and the relevant laws and regulations, including utilization of the data by Wizz Air employees and the transmission of the data within or outside Hungary as specified herein.**

In relation to your data included in the passenger list Wizz Air’s data processing is based on the Gov. Decree 25/1999 (II. 12.) on Passenger Transport by Air, other data processing by Wizz Air is based on your voluntary consent under Section 5 of Act CXII of 2011 on Informational Self-Determination and Freedom of Information (“Info Act”).In certain cases we also need to process your sensitive personal data (as defined in Section 3.3 of the Info Act) when you request special assistance from us and/or an airport operator (such as the provision of oxygen), or when you provide us with information about your fitness for fly (for instance if you are pregnant).By providing any personal data that, is or could be considered to be, “sensitive personal data” you explicitly agree that we may collect, use, share with third parties (such as the departure or the destination airport or ground handling companies at such airports or our call center) and transfer outside the European Economic Area this personal data, as described in this Policy. This is to ensure that we can satisfy your request for special assistance or for safety reasons (your fitness for fly).If you withdraw your consent or do not provide a data, it may mean that we will not be able to provide all or parts of the services you have requested. Please note that in these circumstances you will not be able to cancel or obtain a refund of any fees you have paid.

2.4 Use of your personal data

The purposes for which we use your personal data are:  
a.) to deliver the services you have purchased from us or to facilitate the purchase of third parties’ services or products on our website, via our application or through our call center (data used for this purpose includes all of the data collected during the booking process: such as passenger name, nationality, gender, phone number, e-mail address, credit or bank card details, information on special care, flight details, confirmation number, date of birth, place of birth, details of travel documents, and WIZZ Account number);  
b.) to provide services, offers and reminders tailored to your requirements (we use for this purpose personal data such as name and contact details, details of your historical searches);  
c.) to communicate with you (for instance to send you reminder emails, or notifications about any flight disturbance) (we use for this purpose personal data such as name and contact details, flight);  
d.) to communicate with you to carry out customer satisfaction survey for analytics purposes, for quality improvements, for service developments, to improve the performance of the website, to measure the success of our advertising campaigns or to tailor services to your needs (we use for this purpose your name and contact details and historic booking details)  
e.) to support other administrative purposes (including but not limited to accounting and billing, auditing, credit or other payment card verification, anti-fraud screening (including the use of credit reference agency searches and payment card validation checks), immigration and customs control, safety, security, health, administrative and legal purposes and systems testing, maintenance and development) (we may use any of the data that we collected from you, as appropriate).

### 3\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD PARTIES

3.1 Your personal data may be shared within the Wizz Air Group. For more information about Wizz Air Group, please click [here](https://wizzair.com/en-gb/information-and-services/about-us/company-information). In addition disclosure of your data to other parties may be necessary to ensure the smooth provision of the products, services and information you request.

3.2. We may also disclose your personal data to third parties for the purpose described in this Policy:  
\- travel agents and other third parties who you book travel or other services through;  
\- third party service providers whose services you purchased (such as insurance, transfer services) on our website, in our application or via our call center;  
\- our partners in loyalty schemes that you have joined;  
\- ground handling companies and airports to provide the service you requested;  
\- credit card companies, payment service providers to process the payments you initiated on our website, in our application or via our call center;  
\- third parties running customer surveys on our behalf;  
\- other third party service providers involved by us for – inter alia - data processing;  
\- third parties, such as law firms and law courts, in order to enforce or apply any contract with you;  
\- government authorities or enforcement bodies such as the police and regulatory authorities, upon their request and only as required by the applicable law or to protect our rights or the safety of our customers, staff and assets.

3.3. Travel agents and other third parties. When you purchase any service at our ticketing agent at an airport you hereby expressly consent to the processing of your personal data by the ticketing agent in accordance with this Policy. Please click [here](https://wizzair.com/en-gb/information-and-services/about-us/privacy-policy/list-of-service-providers) to see which legal entity will process your personal data.

3.4. Third party service providers. When you purchase the service of a third party service provider on our website, in our application or via our call center we transfer your personal data to facilitate the purchase.The data processing of such third parties may also be governed by their own privacy policies. Please review the privacy policies on the website of such third parties directly for more information about their data processing practices. In certain cases, both our and such third party’s terms and conditions and privacy policies shall be accepted to obtain the relevant service.Furthermore, we also receive information about you from third parties, for instance when you participate in a loyalty program.For more information about the data transfer to/from third parties, please click [here](https://wizzair.com/en-gb/information-and-services/about-us/privacy-policy/third-party-providers).

3.5. Call center. We engage third party suppliers for the provision of call center services for us. You can find more information about these suppliers [here.](https://wizzair.com/en-gb/information-and-services/about-us/privacy-policy/call-centres) The call center is processing your personal data in accordance with this Policy. The call is being recorded and may be connected with other reservation data to ensure quality and for possible future complaints handling. Complaints submitted electronically, via post or via email are also archived, and may be connected with other reservation data for possible future complaints handling.

3.6. Border police and immigration authorities. In certain countries, Wizz Air is required by law to give border control agencies access to booking and travel information. Therefore, any information we hold about you and your travel arrangements may be disclosed to the customs and immigration authorities of your place of departure or your destination.In addition, laws in several countries require Wizz Air to collect passport and associated information for all passengers prior to travel to or from those countries. When required, Wizz Air will provide this information to the relevant customs and immigration authorities.

### 4\. SECURITY

4.1 We take appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure the protection of your personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, in particular where the processing involves the transmission of data over a network, and against all other unlawful forms of processing. We pay special attention to the safe transmission of the personal and financial data. This data is transmitted from your computer to the booking server of Wizz Air through encrypted channels with the support of the state-of-the-art Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

4.2 If we transfer data to a country outside the European Union in accordance with this Policy we cannot guarantee that the data will be protected in accordance with EU data protection laws and regulations.

By continuing to use our services and by providing us with any personal data, you expressly consent to such transfers, storage and processing of your personal data outside the country in which you are located and outside the European Economic Area, including to countries where under local law you may have fewer legal rights.

### 5\. USE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR MARKETING OR OTHER PURPOSES

5.1 During the use of our website cookies are stored by your browser on your device. Read more about the cookies used by Wizz Air by clicking here. Our aim is to ensure that our website offers visitors what they are looking for and provides them with the most relevant marketing communication. In order to achieve this goal, we may use your data for analytics purposes, for quality improvements, for service developments, to improve the performance of the website, to measure the success of our advertising campaigns or to tailor services to your needs. For these purposes we may transfer your non-personally identifiable data such as, but not limited to, anonymous demographic information and online behaviour to our contracted partners (e.g. third party service providers listed in clause 3. or banks issuing WIZZ branded credit/debit cards, with special benefits). We store data sent by your browser and device to our website during the reservation process. No such data will be disclosed to third parties except in aggregate, non-personally identifiable forms.

5.2 You may receive special offers from us if you have requested such communication by subscribing to our newsletter, or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion or if you become a member of the Wizz Discount Club. By subscribing to newsletters, becoming Wizz Discount Club member or providing your details as listed above you expressly consent – being aware of adequate information on the data processing – to receiving direct marketing communications including direct marketing or special offers of Wizz Air or of our contracted partners (e.g. banks issuing WIZZ branded credit/debit cards, with special benefits; Wizz Tours Ltd.) and to receive reminder emails in relation to your bookings which you did not finish. For the purposes of sending you such direct marketing communications/special offers, we will process your following personal data: name and e-mail address or phone number. For the purpose of the reminder email we will store and use the following data of your search: selected starting point and destination, oneway or return flight, departure|arrival times, number of passengers, selected fare type, total amount of fare price, the user is newsletter subscriber, booking type (normal, WDC, group), selected services, language of the site/Wizz Air application. We will store this set of data for four days.

5.3 Such consent is voluntary. You can unsubscribe any time without giving any reason, free of charge by clicking here or the link provided in each newsletter, or via changing preferences in your Wizz profile, or by sending a letter to  Laurus Offices | Kőér street 2/A | Building B | H-1103 | Budapest, Hungary.

### 6\. MISCELLANEOUS

6.1 If you register on our website, we assume that you are happy for us to process your data given to us during the registration process and you will not have to provide your data again when making further bookings.

6.2 When you make a booking you will be given a confirmation code. This appears in the confirmation email you receive after the booking. We advise that your confirmation code should be kept confidential at all times. Disclosure of your confirmation code to others may allow them to access your booking details and itinerary through our system.

6.3 Your personal data and the contracts concluded by and between you and Wizz Air are kept in our reservation system. If you would like to get information about your passenger registration record or any data stored by Wizz Air, about the data processing and data processing entities (if any), or would like to request that your data be changed or deleted, please contact us by choosing the category of “General questions/ requests, regarding Privacy Policy” on [this link](https://book.wizzair.com/en-GB/Claims).

6.4 As regards any data processing falling under the scope of the Info Act, you are entitled to the following rights and remedies: You have the right to request information on the data processing, and to request the rectification, erasure or blocking of the personal data. If it is allowed under the applicable law, you can also object to the data processing. In the unexpected case when the rights related to the personal data are breached, you may turn to the Hungarian Authority for Data Protection and Freedom of Information (Nemzeti Adatvédelmi és Információszabadság Hatóság, 1125 Budapest, Szilágyi Erzsébet fasor 22/C.; telephone: +36-1+391-1400; telefax: +36-1-391-1410; e-mail: ugyfelszolgalat@naih.hu) or to the competent court. Your detailed rights and remedies are set out in the sub-chapters 13-17 and sub-chapter 30 of the Info Act.

6.5 If we change this Privacy Policy, we will publish the updated version of it on our website, wizzair.com.

6.6 We process your personal data for the time required for the performance of the above purposes or for the period of limitation prescribed in the relevant laws.

6.7 The wizzair.com website provides links to other websites for your convenience and information. Please be aware that these sites may be owned and run by other companies and organizations and have different security and privacy policies. Wizz Air has no control over and takes no responsibility for any information, material, products or services contained on or accessible through those websites.

6.8 This Privacy Policy is effective from 23 December 2015.
